It's time. Get up.
I got it, Dad.
- I need to make a list.
- It's for a birthday present.
It's two or three, okay?
Yeah, look, I'll pick the best gift I can give you.
That's a smart way to do it. Make a list.
Can I write it down?
I can write it down.
- It's fun.
I want to go to the park later today.
No, because we're going to Oakland.
It's a kiss.
I'll talk to you later.
I'm sorry about that.
I wonder when we're going to put it out.
This is Y.
"Happiness" has no "Y" and no "Y".
My name is Chris Gardner.
When I was 28, I met my father for the first time.
I made up my mind.
When I had a baby.
I want my kids to know who my father is.
Let me tell you about some of my biological language.
This is what I call a bus ride story.
What's that?
It's a time machine, right?
It looks like a time machine.
It's a time machine. I want to go with you.
This machine...
The machine above the knee...
This guy has a time machine.
I'm traveling through the past.
This isn't a time machine.
It's a portable bone density gauge.
I'm selling these medical devices for a living.
Thank you for the opportunity to talk to me.
- Thank you very much.
It's unnecessary. It's high.
That's right, then again.
It's twice as high, but it's a little better than the X-ray.
- What's going on?
- Something was wrong.
I'm not going to meet Christopher today.
No, Chris, I have to work at 7:00.
We have to go to Oakland.
I took Christopher home, fed him, took him to the bathroom.
You're going to sleep and be back here till 7:00?
I got a tax return today.
- What are you gonna do?
A car with a nice yellow shoe.
That's my car.
There's no parking near the hospital.
This is the way to go when you're in a hurry.
Thank you. Thank you.
- Maybe it'll be all right in the next quarter.
I have to sell more than two a month for rent and daycare.
I need to sell another one.
I can't pay a parking ticket for parking violations.
The problem is...
I don't sell a single one these days.
Since when do you hate macaroni and cheese?
Since I was born.
- What is this?
This is a gift for Christopher.
- I'm working with my partner, Cynthia.
It's for adults. Christopher can't do it, and neither can she.
How are we gonna do this?
I'm going to put all the sides together in the same color.
I paid my taxes.
I'm still here. I'm applying for a delay.
- You've already filed for a delay.
I'll get you $650 next month.
What about interest?
- What about the fine?
You're not going to do this?
- I have to go to work.
- I'll get the bed.
A couple of days ago, I was told about the research I asked for.
And that's what we're going to do with a comprehensive survey of the economy.
And I'm sure you're all displeased about that, and I am.
But you have to be truthful.
And we need action to make things better.
Failure is not allowed to overcome problems.
The federal budget is in crisis.
We're facing an expanding deficit.
By the end of the year, on September 30, it'll be close to $80 billion.
The size of the deficit is more than the total federal budget for 1957.
That's almost $80 billion.
The interest rate is embedded in the national debt.
20 years ago, in 1960,
The federal government's personal costs were $13 billion.
Today, that's 75 billion.
In the last 20 years, the population has increased by 23.3 percent.
Can you give me a minute or two?
What's your job?
- I'm a stockbroker, you know.
Shouldn't I go to college?
It's not necessary. It's strong in numbers.
- That's it.
I'll let you borrow my car for the weekend.
- Give it back Monday.
I still remember that time.
To me, everyone seemed very happy.
Why do they look like that?
I'll be home by 6:00.
After work, I'll go to the sales office.
- I'm looking for a job.
What kind of work?
I was a kid.
When I was a kid, I read my math book in a week.
I'm going to see what kind of job you have.
What kind of work?
The stockbroker.
- You're a stockbroker?
You're not an astronaut?
Don't say that, Linda.
I'd like to go outside today and check.
I need you to call Sales.
I don't want to tell you anything about sales phones.
I have to make three calls before the office opens.
I'm about to pay my rent next week, you know?
Maybe not.
I haven't paid for two months.
It's three months next week.
I've been working a double shift for four months, Chris.
All right, you sell all your stocks, and then you get out of that business.
Linda, I'm doing that right now.
I'm doing this for my family.
It's for you and Christopher.
What's wrong with that?
Linda, what are you doing?
This part of my life is called a squirrel or a squirrel.
I have a request.
I'm just going to put this here for five minutes, so can you look?
I can't move for a meeting nearby.
I'm going to take a look at this for a second.
This is a dollar, and I'll give you an extra when I get back.
Okay, this is not worth much, so I can't sell it.
I can't sell it. I need a job.
Chris, Tim Brophy from the Resources department.
- This way.
Let's see if we can find out if our company's accepting applications for vocational training.
This is the best I can do. This is a field trip.
This is Jay Toisel of our company. He's overseeing the Uitra Resource Set.
I mean, I'm his secretary.
As you can see, we've got a lot of applications, so...
I always put my résumé here, but I don't see it.
- Thank you.
I have to go now.
I'll return this later.
- Thank you.
What have I done to believe in a hippie?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I know.
Like I said, this part of my life is called a squirrel or a squirrel.
Don't move! Don't move! Stay right there!
Stop it, stop it!
Don't move, stop him, stop the train!
There are 20 people who participate in this program every six months.
There's only one person who can get a job.
I had three blank lines after I graduated from high school.
I didn't need that ticket.
Go to sleep, it's too late.
This is a three-inch puzzle.
It's made up of different colored parts that can rotate or rotate.
And then you're going to have to arrange each side to be a beta color.
This Rubik's Cube caused a whirlwind in the gift field in 1981.
It's not that easy.
We met a math professor at the University of San Francisco.
He needed just 30 minutes.
That's how far I've come.
And as you can see, we still have a long way to go.
Jim Finetti has reported.
Get up.
Eat it.
- Well, then again, Mom.
- You're gonna have to get it out of your system and go home.
Now, go ahead and say goodbye to this one, because I'm not gonna take it.
And then again, and then again, and again, and again, and again, and again, and again, and again.
I don't need to tell you the clever part of the escape.
I'm on my way, Mom.
Come on, people.
It's P-P-Y, but in happiness, I-I-I is right.
- Is that an adjective?
It's not spelled right.
- Is the fucking spelling right?
But the tagline is bad. You don't have to learn it.
It's used in adult speech, anger, or something else.
- I don't want to use it.
It says something on the back of your bag.
My last name.
We have a nickname.
- Oh, yeah, what's going on?
- Did your dad have a nickname?
- I'm going to have to get my head around it.
My dad grew up in Ludhiana, near Texas.
They were all wearing carboy hats, and they were all wearing tangalong hats.
And yet, the hat looked small, so they all nodded their heads and called him "Honey".
- That's the kind of hat that Hoss wears.
I've got a hot cart light in Bonanza.
- How do you know Bonanza?
- You're watching TV on your daycare?
What time is it? I'm watching TV.
It's after your eight, or after lunch.
I made a list of gifts.
- What did you put on it?
- I heard you're watching TV all the time.
- It's a history show for the Navy.
It's not the Navy.
I'll watch it at home on TV.
I'm paying 150 bucks a month and I'm sitting there all day.
I don't care if you're watching TV.
If you don't like Navy TV, you'll have to pay an extra fee.
You're late for your payment, and you're complaining.
At least you can move the dog upstairs, or you can have your own room.
I'll see you later.
I was waiting for Jay Toisel, the head of Vitra Resources.
And the sound of that name made me feel so good about him giving me a job and a hug.
I wanted them to know that I was strong in numbers and that I was good at connecting with people.
- Good afternoon, Mr. Toisel.
- This is Mr. Tissell, Chris Gardner.
I asked you to share this with me personally, to get to know you.
I thought I'd meet you here, and I'm very happy to talk to you.
This is part of my petition.
I'll give you a call.
- I see, have a nice day.
What are you doing?
My name is Chris Gardner. Dr. Delsey, please.
I'm a little late to call you.
If you don't have the support...
Yeah, still... half an hour?
Yeah, that's great, that's great, thank you, thank you.
Oh, my God!
This part of my life...
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
It's called the "running" "running"
Oh, my God!
Wait a minute!
Oh, wait a minute!
That's my stolen machine.
She's with the guy, and he's selling machines.
That's not possible.
I was the only one who could sell it in the Bay Area.
I threw all my money away and invested in this machine.
This was a breakthrough machine.
- Oh, this is how I feel.
It's a hell of a job.
I didn't know. Doctors and hospitals...
I've been told that it was an unnecessary luxury.
I kindly asked the landlord to take a memorial.
That's why I was losing my living expenses for a month.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hey, give it back!
Hey, you...
- Who is he?
- Did you forget?
You don't have one?
- Yeah, I know.
I'm going to go.
I'm going to be a mother.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- It's a basketball game.
I didn't know it was basketball.
Did you think it was an ant keeper or a microscope or something?
- No, I'm not.
Okay, so, open it up, open it up.
- Can you open the paper?
I couldn't find you there.
The machines were stolen, the dropouts tracked down...
I can tell you anything.
- I can tell you anything, Chris.
What the hell? Are you mad?
- What are you talking about?
Roy, Roy, Roy, Roy, Roy, Roy, Roy!
You can't do it when no one's around?
It's all over the place. It's all over the place.
- I want to keep the house clean.
You need to calm down, Linda.
I'm gonna get out of this. It's all going to work out, okay?
When I got pregnant, I said the same thing.
- Don't you believe me?
I'm going to take a taxi.
This is Chris Gardner.
Well, what's it for?
I filed my application for vocational training a month ago.
I'd like to talk a little bit about that.
I'm sorry, I'm on my way to Noah's Bay, Chris.
- You have to be careful.
Actually, I'm on my way to Noah's Valley.
Can I have you on board?
- All right, get in the car.
When I was in the Navy working under a doctor...
The doctor loved golf, and he was a golf-blind man every day, for hours.
I'm going to do a real medical procedure.
When I was alone at work...
And that's why I'm used to having a decision-making role, and...
Mr. Toisel, listen to me. This is important.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. This is impossible.
- I can do it.
- I can do some stupid things.
- No, you can't, you can't.
This way.
Oh, I'm going to make a mess of it.
I'm sorry about that.
It's rotating around the center of the rotating axis, so the center of the rotating axis doesn't move.
The center is yellow, and this side is yellow.
The red is in the center. This is the red side.
- All right, take it easy.
You can't ride it all day.
- I can do it.
- I can do that.
I don't think anyone can.
Well, I've been there.
There you go. It's almost here.
Oh, my God.
- It's almost over.
Look at that.
It's almost done.
- This is me.
It's all right.
I'll see you around.
So, which way?
I'm sorry. Which one do you want to go to?
We're two or three blocks away.
- Can't you just give it back?
Oh, stop it!
Where are we going?
You son of a bitch, pay me!
- Please stop.
- Please, please.
He should have paid.
- I'm sorry about that.
- I'm really sorry.
I'm going to catch him!
I'm going to kill you!
Oh, my God.
Stop and shit.
Stop it! Stop it!
The door closes.
Please stay away from the door.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, you are not
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
- If you do.
I'm sorry I didn't get home on time.
Chris, I didn't get to work on time.
Is Christopher on his way home, too?
I'm going out, Chris.
- I didn't hear what you just said.
I'll get my stuff together and take the kids.
I'm getting out of here.
I'm going to cut the phone.
- Linda, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
It was the right thing to do when I started thinking about Thomas Jefferson.
The Declaration of Independence...
And part of the right to live... freedom and happiness.
I remember what I thought.
How did he put that part of the seizure of the seagull in there?
That's probably the only thing we can pursue.
Maybe, in fact, you'll never get it.
No matter what you do...
How did he know?
Linda, Linda, what are you doing?
- If you did.
- Who is it?
I'm going to tell you about Dean Vitra.
Yeah, are you okay?
I'm fine. You want to come over here and talk to me?
Yes, of course I will.
I'll tell you what, come over here tomorrow morning.
I'm going to do an interviewing for a job interview.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Wait a minute, please.
If I did,
- I had a pen.
I want you to write down your phone number and call Janis, your secretary.
- She'll teach you the details.
- So that's 415 minus 415.
- 864 to 864.
- What are you doing?
- Yes, the number is 4796 - Yes, 415-864-0256.
- Yes, call her tomorrow.
- Yes, you are.
- I'll see you soon.
864-0256
4796, this is Janice.
- Chris, what are you doing?
Have you seen Linda and Christopher?
- I don't know, did you see the game last night?
I didn't see it!
I'm sorry, did Linda and Christopher not come?
- No, I didn't see it.
Moon's got 17 seconds left and he's got three points.
Wayne, Wayne, Wayne, what are you doing?
I can't talk about numbers right now.
- Do you have any problems with the numbers?
- I'm lending you money.
It's $14 each.
I'll get it back to you right away.
I need money. I need money.
So 14 is a number?
Oh, you took your son away from me.
- Are you listening to me?
Don't pick up my kid again.
Don't you understand what I'm saying?
Don't run away from me when I'm talking.
- Do you want to say goodbye?
- You want to break up?
Linda, tell me what you want!
I'm going to tell you what to do.
You're the god of the plague, you hear me?
- You don't have to.
- Then be happy, Linda!
You'll find happiness.
I'm going to live with Christopher.
- Did you hear that?
Christopher's going to live with me!
All right, let's get going.
- I'm sorry, but you've got to go.
- Where's Mommy?
Mom said she'd come to pick me up today.
Oh, I know.
I've already spoken to my mom.
Where are you sleeping tonight?
Can I ask you something else?
Yeah, well, I'm the one who's doing it.
You're lucky, and Dad's happy, too, right?
- I'm going to get it.
Let's go to bed with Dad.
You're gonna have to live in the house you're in.
I'm not going to lie.
Well, listen to me, I need you to pay the rent.
I can't wait any longer.
Oh, trust me, Charlie, I'll get it right away.
Why don't you move to the Mission Inn Motel two blocks away?
That's half the price we're paying now.
Look, Chris, get out of here tomorrow morning.
What, we're going out tomorrow morning?
I asked for a painter.
- All right, give me a little time.
Well, I'll paint it myself.
I've got a little more time, and I'm gonna have to deal with my son.
I don't know. Wait a week. You paint it.
What about Chris Gardner?
Yeah, what happened?
- It's a debt to the city of San Francisco.
Please pay for all parking tickets, or I'll stay the night.
That's it.
Please check tomorrow at 9:30 a.m.
- Whatever. - Please stay until this review is over.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, I can't spend the night here.
- I'm going to pick up my son.
I'm scheduled to be interviewed tomorrow morning at 10:15 at Dean Whitelaw.
- I can't stay here tomorrow morning at 9:30.
What are you gonna do with your son?
- Is there anyone else?
We're going to have to ask you to join us at the social services.
All right, I'll make the call.
- If you did.
Can I help you?
I want you to pick up Christopher Daycare. I can't go.
Just take care of me for one night.
What's the matter?
I'll pick you up tomorrow.
I'm going to...
You're going to send me. I'm going to pick you up.
Please, Linda.
- Why can't I take you to the park?
After the daycare, to the Golden Gate.
- How are you?
All right, take me to the park.
And, uh, give it back, will you?
Look, give me my son back.
Do you hear me?
What about Linda?
I'll take you home around 6:00.
I got it.
Thank you. Thank you.
I'll see you later.
With this?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I know.
Mr. Gardner, what are you doing?
This way.
This is it.
What's the answer?
This is Chris Gardner.
Good afternoon.
Chris Gardner. Chris Gardner. Glad to see you again.
Chris Gardner, I'm very pleased to meet you.
I mean, until now, when you've been sitting for 30 minutes...
I was trying to tell you something.
That was the excuse I came here dressed like this.
First of all, I'm here to prove myself.
I'm sure you all appreciate your sincerity and diligence.
I didn't think anything of team play.
So the truth is...
I was arrested for parking violation.
The fine?
I ran from the police all the way here.
What did you do before you were arrested?
I was painting my apartment.
Are they dry yet?
Well, I hope so.
Jay says you're a pretty good guy.
He was waiting outside the building.
You've got a device that weighs 40 pounds for a month.
- I heard you've been cut off.
- Do you want to learn a job?
You're starting with yourself, aren't you?
Of course you do.
- Jay?
How many times have you met Chris?
I don't remember.
- Have you ever seen a dress like this?
It's always a dress and tie.
First of all, it's the classroom.
- High school?
- How many in your class?
It was a small town.
I was the best in my class in radar.
In the Navy, there were 20 people in the class.
I have something to say.
My strength is...
When you're asked a question and you don't know the answer,
I'll say, "I don't know".
But I'll say it.
I know how to find the answers, and I will.
Don't you think that's fair?
Chris, what's going on?
What would you say if a man showed up for an interview...
The man without the shirt...
What would you say if I hired him?
I'm sure he was wearing some really cool pants.
Chris, I don't know how you dressed up like a garbage collector.
- But you're a lot more than that.
Hey, call Jay. Can I talk to you right now?
All right, I'll get back to you, Jay.
What do you mean, Jay-Z?
Yeah, I'll call you sometime tomorrow.
What are you talking about?
- You're not gonna get paid.
I didn't realize that.
My situation has changed.
- And I need to make sure...
This is tonight.
I'll get you in, I promise.
You know how I'm gonna look at my friends when you run away?
Yes, he is a fool, a fool.
Yeah, you fool, there's no way around that.
You're the only one.
This is tonight.
It's free.
I don't even have a legitimate promise to get a job.
At the end of the course, we'll have 20 to one intern.
If that man...
I couldn't even apply for six months of training...
To become a salesman...
The only asset I have is a six-month...
We're gonna have to sell six of those measuring instruments.
If we sell it all, we can make a living.
- I'll carry it.
I got it.
I'm going to get it.
I'm going to New York.
My sister's boyfriend is...
I opened a restaurant, and I work there.
So I'm going to New York.
I'm going to live with Christopher.
I'm your mother.
I should be living with my mom.
I'll take it from here, okay?
Look, I can't take care of you.
What are you gonna do with the money?
I was interviewed by Dean Whitelaw for his vocational training...
And I got it.
I'm going to do my best in training.
From salesman to trainee.
No, it's not like that.
I have to go.
I'll tell you because I love you, okay?
And then...
Take care of her, Chris.
I know. I know.
- Dean Whitelaw.
Yes, I'd like a message to Mr. Jay Whistler.
- My name is Chris Gardner.
The message is:
Thank you for your permission to participate in the training.
Thank you very much for your permission to participate.
Is that all?
Yes, more than that.
- I'll take it.
Well, then.
- And be careful.
Be careful. Let's go.
- Did you get there?
- Hey, what's the date today?
- What?
- What day is Saturday?
- Do you want to play basketball?
So, what do you say we sell one of those bone density meters?
- You want to go?
Dad, I'm going to be a pro.
I'm going to be a pro.
- Yes, you are.
Oh, I don't know.
He's as good as your dad was when he was your age.
Even so, my dad was below average.
So your level is probably...
Well, that's good.
You're better than this, you're better than many other things.
I don't want to practice shooting all day.
- You got it?
Look at this.
All right, that's it.
Oh, my God.
Don't tell anyone.
You can't do that.
Even my father.
- You hear me?
Have a dream.
Take care of that.
You can't do anything on your own.
People say you can't.
If you want to do something, you just do it. That's it.
Let's get out of here.
Dad, why did you move to the motel?
I told you, Dad's gonna get a better job.
- I want you to believe me, okay?
Yeah, this is it, that's it.
Dad, Mom, when are you coming home?
I don't know, Christopher.
Dad, listen to me.
One day, a man was drowning.
The boat came up, and I said, "Hey, can you help me?"
He said, "No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
And then another boat came and said, "Do you need any help?"
He said, "No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
And then he drowned and went to heaven.
And he said, "Oh, my God, why didn't you help me?
God said, "I'm gonna get two big boats out of here, asshole.
What's up?
Okay, that's funny. You put your hands out.
- Thank you very much.
- I'll give you the license.
All the information you need is here.
Thank you for the deal.
Thank you. Thank you.
One hundred, two hundred, twenty, forty, forty-five, forty-six.
Seven, eight, nine, ten.
Thank you. Thank you.
- Oh, you want one?
Okay, I want one.
- How much is this?
This part of my life is called the practice training.
The 1200 Building is Merdy Industries and San Cow Oil.
The building across the street is freight shipping.
In two or three weeks, the phone list...
It's got the phone number of the employee...
From the Fortune 500 financial district...
You're in charge of 60 Fortune companies.
You're primarily making sales calls to prospective customers.
If you're having lunch with a customer, have breakfast.
You can even babysit for your customers, do anything to be close to them.
We expect you to be able to match your customers' needs and goals.
One of the many financial plans... you can attract customers on the Rile.
Let's cook the fish we caught.
You're here because you know who's on the other side.
You're here because you think you're the only person.
If there's one man here, he'll be a one-horned person.
He was a man.
I changed this to this.
We're paying $800,000 for the commission.
I'm going to give you this. Can you help me?
This will be your Bible.
It's always with this when you eat.
- I'm always with you when you drink.
X is equal to X's perspective.
So, X's prospects are equal to X's customers.
X customers are equal to X dollars.
- In the company's pocket.
Last year, one intern got a score of 96.4 on a written exam.
He wasn't selected. This isn't a simple pass-through test.
Our assessment tools evaluate candidates individually.
For your safety, take 100 points.
Well, let's take a break and go home in ten minutes.
Chris, how are you?
- I'm fine, thank you.
Have you quit yet?
No, it's a ten-minute break.
You jump out, you grab something, and then you go home, ready for the exam.
Yes, I remember.
We were an hour, not three hours like you.
We didn't do the world market, and we weren't bothered by taxation.
And I'm still in pain. I remember something funny.
There's a cute girl in my class.
I don't remember her name, but her face...
I want to apologize for meeting an old friend.
- It was a funny story.
Hey, you stupid son of a bitch, are you okay?
What were you thinking?
What are you doing?
I was trying to cross the street.
- Are you all right?
- Where are my shoes?
- Don't hit me with your shoes!
Hey, what's up?
I lost my shoes.
Hey, where are we going?
- We should wait for the police.
Hey, you got hit by a car. Go to the hospital.
I'm competing in Dean Wheatler's business training.
Hey, I'm not wearing shoes on either side.
Oh, yeah, thank you.
Dad, you know what?
- I'm not wearing shoes on either side.
- Tell me what happened.
He was hit by a car.
- Was he hit by a car?
- A little to the right of the office.
- No, what part of your body?
- I'll see you later, Mr. Tu.
- Where were you on the street?
Stop doing that. I'm going to hurt you.
Yes, thank you.
I'll keep that in mind.
And here we are again.
- You're the one who qualifies.
The qualified people are interested in investing and have the money to invest.
- All right, Chris. - I know.
Can you get me some coffee?
Flakesh, the manager of the workplace, the day-to-day service.
My name is Chris Gardner, and I'm calling Mr. Michael Anderson.
Yes, I'll have lunch with you this Thursday.
So, next time, I figured it out, and I won't disappoint.
Yes, thank you.
Somebody get us some doughnuts.
- Chris, what are you doing?
The feeling of underestimation and denial of value.
If you were Mr. Ronald Fryer,
Good morning. My name is Chris Gardner.
I'm Dean Whitelaw.
Yes, I have very valuable information about taxes...
Yes, thank you.
And then, by four o'clock, we catch a bus and head to a place where we don't spell happiness.
And then I crossed the city.
I got home at 10:00.
- Hey, Chris, what are you doing?
I know, I'll get it right away, Ralph.
I can get it.
If anyone brings in most of the money, they'll be hired in six months.
If it is Chris Gardner, please, Mr. Walter Hobb.
We've all been trying to improve the way we check customer lists.
- From the bottom to the top.
I'm the CEO of the Doorsman.
The rest of us work until 7:00, but I had Christopher.
I had to do a nine-hour job for other people.
Hello, my name is Chris Gardner. I'm on the phone with Dean Whitelaw.
I don't want to waste my time...
I didn't put my phone down between calls.
I understand. Thank you very much.
If you don't leave the speaker...
I realized I was getting eight minutes more a day.
Good morning. My name is Chris Gardner.
- I'm calling from Dean Whitelaw.
So I didn't waste my time in the bathroom.
Yeah, I'm really excited about the opportunity.
I got it. It's okay. Thank you.
But, you know, if you do something like this...
Two months later, I didn't have time to update my phone list.
And we're confident about that, too.
It's the Water Ribbon office.
Hello, my name is Chris Gardner, please, Mr. Water Ribbon.
- What do you need?
I'm on the phone with Dean Whitelaw.
Wait a minute, please.
- If you could, Mr. Ribbon.
If my name is Chris Gardner, I'm Dean Whitelaw.
- Hey, Chris. - What's going on?
I'd like to have the opportunity to talk to you about our products.
I'm sure we can do something to help.
Will you be here in 20 minutes?
I just had a cancellation.
I'll be out for a few minutes before the Forty Niners.
- It's Monday night football, you know.
- I'll see you in a minute.
I'm sorry, thank you.
Chris, what happened?
Hey, you got five minutes?
I've been given permission by Walter Ribbon...
I'm going to Rome for a briefing. You want to move the car?
It'll be a big help. The car's on Samson Street, half a block away. It's a silver cap.
Move the other way. I'm cleaning the road.
I've got this in my desk.
Open the door.
- What do you want to unlock?
Don't lock the other door.
Please, I'm not open.
Oh, no, you can't.
I'm going to go.
- It's a file, Mr. Ribbon.
Thank you.
Oh, no, not at all!
Rachel and Lisztur, get on the phone.
- Hi, how are you?
I have an appointment with Chris Gardner, Mr. Robin.
Oh, you didn't make it a minute apart.
Thank you. Thank you.
- I'm filling in the bill.
Paying the bills.
And the parking tickets.
We don't have a car anymore.
Yeah, I know.
I'll take you out for the weekend.
Two or three doctors.
- It's for sales, right?
Then, maybe, we'll go see the football.
- You sure about that?
- You got it?
All right, here we go.
- Are you sure?
You really are?
- Are you gonna take it to the game?
And maybe we'll go see the game.
Where are you going now, to meet the man I work for?
I don't know.
- What don't you know?
Maybe he said we were going to the game.
- possibly know the meaning of the word - probably the same
No, it's probably the best place for us to go.
Maybe the meaning of "possible" is, maybe it is, maybe it isn't.
- What's the meaning of "probably" "probably"?
So what does "possibly" mean?
- I know what that means.
That means we don't have to go to the game.
- How did you get so smart?
- This is it?
- Mr. Ribbon, what are you doing?
I'm Chris Gardner from Dean Wheatler.
- Oh, my son Christopher.
I'm not going to tell you what to do.
- What are you doing here?
- I broke my promise...
I'm visiting a close friend in the neighborhood.
I wanted to take this opportunity to take the time to thank you for your kind words.
- You must have been waiting for me.
I don't want to take that for granted.
What is that?
Oh, this is the Osteo National bone density gauge.
It's a company I worked for before I started working at WITRA.
- We have a meeting after the game.
- That's right.
We'll go with you.
I'm taking my son, Tim, who's 12.
Where are you going, Tim?
Well, we're sorry about that.
Thank you very much. I'm so sorry about yesterday.
I'm glad you've got a schedule.
- I got it.
You know, be careful.
- Bye, Chris. - Bye, then.
I'll see you around, Christopher.
Hey, you guys want to come with me?
I'll go with you wherever you go.
- Where's your seat?
There's a box seat. Let's go.
- You're sitting in the box?
- It's not really a box.
It's comfortable. Do you want to go?
- That's right, the kids are behind.
What if I put it in your car?
We don't have a car.
- What's wrong?
Looks like it was stung by a bee.
- Are you all right?
Are you allergic or something?
- Where'd you stab him?
- Are you all right?
- Is it painful?
- Let's have a look.
Thomas Jefferson mentioned happiness twice.
In the Declaration of Independence,
It sounds like a strange word in that document.
But he said... he was an artist.
He called the English "the frog". He called them "the frog".
And I stood there that day...
I was thinking about who was stopping me.
My question is, is everything going to be good?
Can I do this?
Walter Ribbon and the Pacific Bell Pension...
There are millions of them.
That's it!
It was a path to another place.
Well, this is...
This is how you look at football.
- Thank you so much.
And, Mr. Robin, I would like to thank you for the opportunity to...
I'm going to explain Dean Whitela's asset management, his ability to...
I believe we are very good...
In every way, I've outdone Morgan Stanley.
In fact, I think you're going to be blown up.
Let's get this straight, Dean Whitelaw, please, to manage your retirement fund.
Look, I can't tell you what I'm going to do. You're new to the area.
I like you, but I don't want you to follow the fund.
That's not gonna happen right away.
Now, relax and enjoy the game.
I did!
I'm not going anywhere.
- Here you go.
Of course, I had two or three ideas.
Chris, I'll talk to you later.
It's nice to meet you, Chris. I'm waiting for your call.
Yes, of course I will. Thank you.
I'll see you later, Christopher.
Four months later, we sold all our measuring instruments.
We seemed to have succeeded.
What are you...
- Is this the fastest animal in the world?
We're doing well.
One day...
That day...
That document brought me back to reality.
This part of my life is called the taxpayer's tax bracket.
If you hadn't paid your taxes...
The government has turned its hands on the bank accounts...
And I'm going to get the money.
Dad, you know what?
No warning, nothing.
I'm not gonna be late. That's my money.
How do you get my money?
I was...
Listen, that's all my money.
It's from my bank account.
It was September 25th.
I remember that day.
If it wasn't, I'd know that day.
I've only got $21.33 in my bank account.
I went bankrupt.
- Are you dressed?
Chris, don't bother with me, Chris.
I'm not bothering you, Ralph. Look, I'll pay you right now.
- I need the money now, not later.
I got it!
Hey, what's going on?
Wayne, give me the $14 back.
I don't have any debt right now.
- What, why?
Why would you say you didn't borrow money?
I helped them move.
We're only two blocks away, Wayne.
It's 200 yards.
Four months, Wayne.
We need the money. We need the money. We need it now.
- I'm sorry, I don't have any.
- Wayne, the money.
My $14! Bring me my money!
- It's all $14 in cash, Wayne.
Dad, look at me.
Dad, you know what?
- Are you going?
- Stay here.
- No, you stay here.
Did you hear what Dad said?
- Dad, where are you going?
Dad, what are you doing?
Dad, wait a minute!
- Dad, I'm going to...
I want to go back to the '60s.
When I was younger, I wanted to see Jimi Hendrix play guitar.
Give me back my time machine.
- Dad, where are you going?
Take your stuff and go.
- Chris, what are you doing?
Dr. Tell, I can't see you. I'm sorry.
Where are we going?
I'm going to see someone else.
I'm tired of it.
I know. I know.
Thank you. It doesn't seem to be working normally.
- I have to go, Chris.
Give me a minute. I'll find out why.
Chris, Chris, can I get you out of here?
- Yeah, I'll fix it right away.
Look, I still have work to do.
I'm really going, Chris.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you for your time. Thank you.
I'll see you soon.
Why are our things here?
Dad, you know what?
- Let's go. - Where are we going?
- Get out of here for a minute.
- I can't stay here tonight.
- Can't you hear me?
Oh, did you hear what I said?
Stop it.
I know.
Hurry up, hurry up.
Wayne, what are you doing?
Get up, get up, get up.
Where are you going?
- I don't know where Dad is going.
It's not a time machine.
Dad, you know what?
That guy said it was a time machine.
- That guy was in the park.
He said time machine.
Yeah, this is a time machine.
No, I'm not.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
All you have to do is press this black button.
Do you want to push it?
Let's do that.
I know.
You, too.
It's right here.
Wait a minute. Where do you want to go?
I don't know. Somewhere in the past.
Close your eyes.
I close my eyes and I see.
Look, I'm gonna push it with you.
Close your eyes, close your eyes.
It'll take two or three seconds.
Oh, I was surprised.
Clear, clear, clear.
- What is it?
- Can't you see that dinosaur?
Look around you, look at the dinosaurs.
- Can you see them?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not not
- Wait, be careful.
Don't set the fire. We're cavemen.
I need this fire because there's no electricity.
And it's cold outside, you know?
- Be careful with that!
Get your bags, get them.
- We'll find somewhere safe.
We need a cave.
The cave?
- We need to find the cave, quickly.
I know.
Look behind you!
Come on. This is the cave. Come on.
There you go, there you go, there you go, there you go.
Go ahead and get in.
Hurry up, hurry up, hurry up.
- Is it safe?
I'm going to go.
- How are you, Jay?
How are you doing?
- You doing all right?
- How are you?
Where are you going?
I'm from Sacramento.
I tried to move two or three people.
They're on the packbell, trying to get us out of here.
I'm trying to get it in here.
So I was invited to play golf.
That's great.
Hey, let's win this game.
Debo, I think someone's got a call.
- Get out of here, come with me.
Thank you.
- Can I ask you a question?
I have a room.
I'll fix this and sell it.
- Just a little repair.
I'm here to help you, but this is my son Christopher.
- Five years old.
- I need a place to stay.
But not adults, just women and children.
The kids can stay, you can go somewhere else.
I want to stay with you.
We're going to...
- Then listen, I need a place to stay.
I'm going to pick up the Grid Memorial, and I'm going to get a reservation there at 5:00.
Hurry up. I've got a line waiting.
- Where are you?
All right, guys, there's only four of us left.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, this guy.
- All right, what?
- Hey, this is my place.
Okay, stop it or not.
Dad, what are you doing?
Stop it, stop it, stop it.
Stop it, stop it!
Get out of the line, both of you.
I told you I was the first to show up on time.
I got here on time. I was in line.
I'm done with my job, I'm taking my son...
I was here on time. I was on time.
He's got a line.
- Who's that?
All right, Rodney, let's get out of the line.
It's over. It's not over.
- What's your favorite color?
What's green?
- What do you like green?
What about trees?
Holy shit.
- Holly, what is it?
It's Christmas stuff.
What's the matter?
Maybe he wants to put us to sleep.
Let's get the Captain American warmed up.
Can you breathe?
- You got it?
- I need to see the meter...
No, no, I'm outside the door.
I'll keep the door open for a while.
If you call, I can hear you.
I want to go home.
That's why I'm taking care of the meter.
Do you hear me?
I'm going outside.
I'll keep the door open, because I'm on the stairs.
If you call, I can hear you.
- You got it?
Believe me, will you?
Believe me on this.
I believe you. I believe you.
I believe you.
- I can't hear you.
It's a kiss.
- It's between the chats, right?
- I'll be right there.
- Can you still hear me?
- Can you hear me?
- I believe you.
- That's it?
- Yeah, I'm going to...
- I don't know, what's up?
I'm all right.
Let's go with your luggage.
- Hey, why don't you put it here?
I'll use another room later.
Let's get out of here.
I'm going to get it.
- What's going on?
It's a trip.
You know, your wife and Martha work at Packbell too, right?
- Yes, I'm working.
I'm going to be a senior at the same time.
We want to retire and maintain our lifestyle.
Without a lot of taxes.
I mean, I don't want anyone else putting their hands in your pocket.
Do you know about the city's tax exemption?
I've learned to finish my work early.
I had to finish my job early.
By 5:00, we'll be in line on the grid.
Hurry up.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
My Captain America.
Dad, Dad, Dad, Dad, Dad, Dad, Dad, you know what?
Shut up, shut up!
- Would you give it to your lady?
- Hey, you're not being polite.
I'm going to go.
Dad, pick that up.
What's important about a free train...
We have to climb the mountain.
We should all be with the mountains.
As you know, the mountains are very high.
And the lowest mountains.
- Amen, preacher!
We know that mountain's here on the grid.
Let's sing it.
Lord, don't move that mountain.
Give me the strength to climb that mountain.
Don't move. I'm not gonna move.
Lord, lead me.
My luggage is so heavy.
I can't take it anymore.
But I won't give up. No, no.
I promised you.
I'll see you at the altar of prayer.
- Lord, please don't move that mountain.
Give me the strength to climb that mountain.
When's the exam?
Tomorrow is the day.
How are you doing?
Of course I did.
Thank you. Thank you.
- What are you doing?
I'm done with it, or I'm going somewhere.
I've got a place to go.
- But I answered all of them.
- Are you?
- What do you think about the graph?
I've been struggling with the back-story problem. What did you write?
- What's the problem with the script?
I know.
Hey, Jeff, I met you at the Fortiners game.
- I've been waiting for your call.
Yeah, give me my number, will you?
Yes, I do. Thank you.
Chris, do you have five bucks?
I'll run upstairs and get it for you, Mr. Fromm.
No, I have to go to Carr's bank by 4:00.
- I'll give it back.
Five dollars is enough. Thank you. Thank you.
It's over. Room assignment is over.
There's no more room.
Today's over, tomorrow's over.
It's full. It's full.
It's over. Go ahead and come back tomorrow.
What's the matter?
Twenty, one, two, three, four.
Now, the vacuum tube and the ferrite-induced magnetic core.
- How much is it?
- What's that?
You want to show me?
Yeah, well, I'm not going to break it.
Otherwise, you're gonna be sleeping in the same room with me for the rest of your life.
I don't care about that.
I'll take care of it.
Get some sleep, all right?
I got it.
- Isn't it cold?
It's all right.
Mom left because of me?
- Mom left because of me.
Don't think about it like that.
My mom left because of her.
And you have nothing to do with that.
- That's good.
That's good, Dad.
All right, get some sleep.
- I like it.
That's good for now, Chris.
- It's all right.
$250, four weeks' living expenses.
One hundred, twenty, forty, sixty, eighty, two hundred.
20, 30, 40, 50, and so on.
- What else?
Thank you. Thank you.
- Do you hear me?
- Are you going to the Society?
So, where are you going?
- Maybe we'll stay at the hotel.
It's just one night.
Can we go back to the cave if you want?
No, I'm not.
- I don't want you to.
What's that?
Yeah, well, when you start something, it's fun, but...
Next thing you know, it's not...
- Like a bus?
Sorry, I shouldn't have laughed.
Sometimes, when I'm moving at night...
I'm passing through houses with lights and people...
Sometimes I hear people laughing.
The next day, after work...
We went to the beach.
Far away from everything.
From everything.
It's just me and Christopher.
- Have you seen me?
Far away from the buses and noise.
And the constant disappointment in my head...
And then I'm going to...
Chris, thank you.
- You're doing well.
Thank you, Chris.
I mean, when I was young...
If you're taking a history test, or anything like that, you're gonna...
I'd have tasted this good feeling in whatever I've accomplished.
So I didn't become one of those people.
- What are you doing?
- How are you, Jay?
Rumor has it that you've taken 31 contracts from Pacific Bell.
Oh, my God.
I met a few people at a ball game, got a card, and I'm working.
You're right.
Well, one more day.
Are you nervous?
- No, it's all right.
Listen to me, whatever happens.
You did a great job, Chris.
I mean it.
Be careful.
Yes, Mr. Johnson, and Chris Gardner and Dean Whitelaw.
Yeah, I just called to say thank you.
I'm going to help you at the seminar last month.
Yes, of course.
I know.
No, that's all.
Thank you. Bye.
Chris, this way.
Mr. Fromm, it's nice to meet you.
- That's a good shirt.
- Hey, Jay, you know what?
- Chris, Chris, can you please move your seat?
I was thinking about wearing a shirt today.
As you know, it's the last day.
All right, thank you, thank you, thank you.
But...
You can wear it tomorrow, okay?
Tomorrow is your first day as a salesman.
If you want to work here as a salesman...
What's up, Chris?
I know.
You're doing great. You're the happiest.
So you're welcome to it.
- Was it as easy as you can see?
- I wish you all the best, Chris.
Oh, my God, Chris.
I almost forgot.
Thank you. Thank you.
This is part of my life.
This little part...
It's called the happy-go-lucky-lucky-lucky.
Christopher, Christopher, come on over here.
Yeah, how many...
Is there a planet?
- Seven to seven?
Nine.
Who's the king of the jungle?
- What are you talking about?
You're not a gorilla?
No, it's the lion.
Oh, the lion, the lion, the lion.
Well, Dad, listen to this, knock knock.
- Who's in there?
Sherby, who?
Shelby comes around the mountains when she comes.
- Knock knock - Who is it?
- There's no one here.
Who's that?
That's funny. I like it.